<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 February 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>13 December 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/13/kathapurkar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/12/13/kathapurkar.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>29 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/29/versteegen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/29/versteegen.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>22 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/22/bowtell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/22/bowtell.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>15 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Consider the following card guessing game introduced by Diaconis and Graham (1981): there is a shuffled deck of $mn$ cards with n distinct cards appearing with multiplicity $m$. In each round, the player has to guess the top card of the deck, and is then told whether the guess was correct or not, the top card is then discarded and then the game continues with the next card. This is known as the partial feedback model. The aim is maximise the number of correct guesses. One possible strategy is the shifting strategy in which the player keeps guessing $1$ every round until the guess is correct in some round, and then keeps guessing $2$, and then $3$ and so on. We are interested in finding the expected score using this strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can restate this problem as finding the expected length of the longest increasing subsequence of the form $123\ldots i$ in a word formed using letters $1$ to $n$ where each letter occurs with multiplicity $m$. In this talk, we show that this number is $m+1 - 1/(m+2)$ plus an exponential error term. This settles a conjecture of Diaconis, Graham, He and Spiro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be at an interface between combinatorics, probability and analysis, and is based on joint work with Alexander Clifton, Yifeng Huang, Sam Spiro and Semin Yoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/15/deb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/15/deb.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>8 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let \(H_1, ..., H_r\) be graphs. We write  \(G(n,p) \to (H_1, ..., H_r)\) to denote the property that whenever we colour the edges of \(G(n,p)\) with colours from the set \([r] := \{1, ..., r\}\) there exists some \(1 \leq i \leq r\) and a copy of \(H_i\) in \(G(n,p)\) monochromatic in colour \(i\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been much interest in determining the asymptotic threshold function for this property. Rödl and Ruciński (1995) determined the threshold function for the general symmetric case; that is, when $H_1=\cdots =H_r$. A conjecture of Kohayakawa and Kreuter (1997), if true, would effectively resolve the asymmetric problem. Recently, the 1-statement of this conjecture was confirmed by Mousset, Nenadov and Samotij (2021+). The 0-statement however has only been proved for pairs of cycles, pairs of cliques and pairs of a clique and a cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk we introduce a reduction of the 0-statement of Kohayakawa and Kreuter’s conjecture to a certain deterministic, natural subproblem. To demonstrate the potential of this approach, we show this subproblem can be resolved for almost all pairs of regular graphs (satisfying properties one can assume when proving the 0-statement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/08/hyde.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/08/hyde.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>18 October 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We show that any Cayley graph on an Abelian group of order 2n and degree $\tilde{\Omega}(\log n)$ has at most $2^{n+1}(1+o(1))$ independent sets. This bound is tight up to the $o(1)$ term whenever the graph is bipartite. Proof techniques include the graph container method of Sapozhenko and the Plünnecke-Rusza-Petridis inequality from additive combinatorics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Aditya Potukuchi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/18/yepremyan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/10/18/yepremyan.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>11 October 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several classical results in Ramsey theory (including famous theorems of Schur, van der Waerden, Rado) deal with finding monochromatic linear patterns in two-colourings of the integers. Our topic will be quantitative extensions of such results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A linear system $L$ over $\mathcal{F}_q$ is common if the number of monochromatic solutions to $L=0$ in any two-colouring of $\mathcal{F}_q^n$ is asymptotically at least the expected number of monochromatic solutions in a random two-colouring of $\mathcal{F}_q^n$. Motivated by existing results for specific systems (such as Schur triples and arithmetic progressions), as well as extensive research on common and Sidorenko graphs, the systematic study of common systems of linear equations was recently initiated by Saad and Wolf. Fox, Pham and Zhao characterised common linear equations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will talk about recent progress towards a classification of common systems of two or more linear equations. In particular, the uncommonness of an arbitrarily large system $L$ can be reduced to studying single equations implied by $L$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joint work with Anita Liebenau and Natasha Morrison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/11/kamcev.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/10/11/kamcev.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
