<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>21 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/21/kronenberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/21/kronenberg.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>14 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/14/mond.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/14/mond.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Komlós, Sárközy and Szemerédi proved that for sufficiently large $n$, every $n$-vertex graph with minimum degree at least $n/2 + o(n)$ contains a copy of every $n$-vertex tree with maximum degree at most $O(n/\log n)$. We prove the corresponding result for directed graphs. That is, we show that for sufficiently large $n$, every $n$-vertex directed graph with minimum semidegree at least $n/2 + o(n)$ contains a copy of every $n$-vertex oriented tree whose underlying maximum degree is at most $O(n/\log n)$. This improves a recent result of Mycroft and Naia, which requires the oriented trees to have underlying maximum degree at most $\Delta$, for any constant $\Delta$ and sufficiently large $n$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/07/kathapurkar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/07/kathapurkar.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>28 February 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/28/fischer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/28/fischer.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>21 February 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Given any graph with lights turned on at each vertex and buttons corresponding to each vertex that toggle the status (on/off) of the vertex together with its neighbourhood, is there always a sequence of button-pushes that turns all of the lights off? This puzzle is answered by a folklore result of Gallai on partitioning the vertex set of a graph into two parts, each inducing a subgraph with specified degree parity conditions. A natural follow-up is to consider partitions satisfying prescribed degree congruence conditions modulo $q$. Recently, Ferber, Hardiman and Krivelevich showed that, for any $0\leq x &amp;lt;q$, almost every $G_{n,1/2}$ has a vertex partition into $q+1$ parts such that each induced subgraph has degrees $x \bmod q$, and asked whether the same holds with $q$ parts. In this talk, we outline why this is not the case; in fact, the distribution of the counts of such `good’ partitions into $q$ parts is asymptotically Poisson. This is joint work with Paul Balister, Emil Powierski and Alex Scott.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/22/tan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/22/tan.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 February 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Latin square of order $n$ is an $n$ by $n$ grid filled with $n$ symbols, so
that every symbol appears exactly once in each row and each column. A
transversal of a Latin square is a collection of cells in the grid which
share no row, column or symbol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ryser-Brualdi-Stein conjecture says that every Latin square of order
$n$ has a transversal with $n-1$ cells if $n$ is even and with $n$ cells if $n$ is
odd. Recently, Keevash, Pokrovskiy, Sudakov and Yepremyan broke a
long-standing bound on this problem by showing that every Latin square
of order $n$ has a transversal with $n-O(\log n/\log \log n)$ cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will discuss how to make further progress on this problem, and in
particular the challenges of using absorption techniques in this setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>31 January 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A well known theorem due to Van der Waerden and dating from 1927 states that in any finite
colouring of the natural numbers there exist arbitrarily long monochromatic arithmetic progressions. Most
Ramsey-theoretical results (finite colourings) have a canonical version. In this setting, the palette of colours
may be infinite but one still would like to characterize all unavoidable sub-structures. For example, the
canonical Van der Waerden’s Theorem, first proved by Erdős and Graham, states that in any colouring
of $[N]$ there exist either arbitrarily long monochromatic arithmetic progressions or arbitrarily long rainbow
arithmetic progressions. In this talk, we shall talk about a canonical version of the polynomial Van der
Waerden’s Theorem, originally proved by Bergelson and Liebman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/girao.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/girao.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>6 December 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let $M_n$ be drawn uniformly from all $n$ by $n$ symmetric matrices with coefficients in {$-1,1$}. We consider the following basic problem: what is the probability $M_n$ is singular? In this talk I will discuss some recent joint work with Marcelo Campos, Matthew Jenssen and Marcus Michelen, where we show the singularity probability is exponentially small. At the heart of the proof is a combinatorial “decoupling” lemma which I suspect has applications well beyond the scope of our work.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/06/sahasrabudhe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/12/06/sahasrabudhe.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>29 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A linear configuration is called common (in $\mathbb{F}_p^n$) if every 2-coloring of $\mathbb{F}_p^n$ yields at least the number of monochromatic instances of a randomly chosen coloring. Saad and Wolf asked whether, analogously to a result by Thomason in graph theory, every configuration containing a 4-term arithmetic progression is uncommon. I will sketch a proof confirming that this is the case and discuss some of the difficulties in finding a full characterisation of common configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/29/versteegen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/29/versteegen.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>22 November 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The $n$-queens problem asks how many ways there are to place $n$ queens on an $n \times n$ chessboard so that no two queens can attack one another, and the toroidal $n$-queens problem asks the same question where the board is considered on the surface of a torus. Let $Q(n)$ denote the number of $n$-queens configurations on the classical board and $T(n)$ the number of toroidal $n$-queens configurations. The toroidal problem was first studied in 1918 by Pólya who showed that $T(n)&amp;gt;0$ if and only if $n \equiv 1,5 \mod 6$. Much more recently Luria showed that $T(n)\leq ((1+o(1))ne^{-3})^n$ and conjectured equality when $n \equiv 1,5 \mod 6$. We prove this conjecture, prior to which no non-trivial lower bounds were known to hold for all (sufficiently large) $n \equiv 1,5 \mod 6$. We also show that $Q(n)\geq((1+o(1))ne^{-3})^n$ for all $n \in \mathbb{N}$ which was independently proved by Luria and Simkin and, combined with our toroidal result, completely settles a conjecture of Rivin, Vardi and Zimmermn regarding both $Q(n)$ and $T(n)$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk we’ll discuss our methods used to prove these results. A crucial element of this is translating the problem to one of counting matchings in a $4$-partite $4$-uniform hypergraph. Our strategy combines a random greedy algorithm to count `almost’ configurations with a complex absorbing strategy that uses ideas from the methods of randomised algebraic construction and iterative absorption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Peter Keevash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/22/bowtell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/11/22/bowtell.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
