<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>29 November 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/staden.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/staden.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>25 October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/25/granet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/10/25/granet.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>10 May 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We will present a new upper bound of $s_r(K_k) = O(k^5 r^{5/2})$ on the Ramsey parameter $s_r(K_k)$ introduced by Burr, Erd&lt;span&gt;ő&lt;/span&gt;s and Lovász in 1976, which is defined as the smallest minimum degree of a graph $G$ such that any $r$-colouring of the edges of $G$ contains a monochromatic $K_k$, whereas no proper subgraph of $G$ has this property. This improves the previous upper bound of $s_r(K_k) = O(k^6 r^3)$ proved by Fox et al. The construction used in our proof relies on a group theoretic model of generalised quadrangles introduced by Kantor in 1980.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with John Bamberg and Thomas Lesgourgues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/10/bishnoi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/05/10/bishnoi.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>21 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Independent sets in bipartite regular graphs have been studied extensively in combinatorics, probability, computer science and more. The problem of counting independent sets is particularly interesting in the $d$-dimensional hypercube {$0,1$}$^d$, motivated by the lattice gas hardcore model from statistical physics. Independent sets also turn out to be very interesting in the context of random graphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of independent sets in the hypercube {$0,1$}$^d$ was estimated precisely by Korshunov and Sapozhenko in the 1980s and recently refined by Jenssen and Perkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will discuss new results on the number of independent sets in a random subgraph of the hypercube. The results extend to the hardcore model and rely on an analysis of the antiferromagnetic Ising model on the hypercube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk is based on joint work with Yinon Spinka.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/21/kronenberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/21/kronenberg.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>14 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For $0 \le r &amp;lt; k$, a Hamiltonian $r$-cycle in a $k$-uniform hypergraph $H$ is a cyclic ordering of the vertices of $H$ in which the edges are segments of length $k$ and every two consecutive edges overlap in exactly $r$ vertices.
We show that for all $0 \le r &amp;lt; k-1$, every Dirac $k$-graph, that is, a $k$-graph with minimum co-degree $pn$ for some $p&amp;gt;1/2$, has (up to a subexponential factor) at least as many Hamiltonian $r$-cycles as a typical random $k$-graph with edge-probability p.
This improves a recent result of Glock, Gould, Joos, Osthus and Kühn, and verifies a conjecture of Ferber, Krivelevich and Sudakov for all values $0 \le r &amp;lt; k-1$.
(Joint work with Asaf Ferber and Liam Hardiman.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/14/mond.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/14/mond.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Komlós, Sárközy and Szemerédi proved that for sufficiently large $n$, every $n$-vertex graph with minimum degree at least $n/2 + o(n)$ contains a copy of every $n$-vertex tree with maximum degree at most $O(n/\log n)$. We prove the corresponding result for directed graphs. That is, we show that for sufficiently large $n$, every $n$-vertex directed graph with minimum semidegree at least $n/2 + o(n)$ contains a copy of every $n$-vertex oriented tree whose underlying maximum degree is at most $O(n/\log n)$. This improves a recent result of Mycroft and Naia, which requires the oriented trees to have underlying maximum degree at most $\Delta$, for any constant $\Delta$ and sufficiently large $n$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/07/kathapurkar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/03/07/kathapurkar.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>28 February 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Given any graph with lights turned on at each vertex and buttons corresponding to each vertex that toggle the status (on/off) of the vertex together with its neighbourhood, is there always a sequence of button-pushes that turns all of the lights off? This puzzle is answered by a folklore result of Gallai on partitioning the vertex set of a graph into two parts, each inducing a subgraph with specified degree parity conditions. A natural follow-up is to consider partitions satisfying prescribed degree congruence conditions modulo $q$. Recently, Ferber, Hardiman and Krivelevich showed that, for any $0\leq x &amp;lt;q$, almost every $G_{n,1/2}$ has a vertex partition into $q+1$ parts such that each induced subgraph has degrees $x \bmod q$, and asked whether the same holds with $q$ parts. In this talk, we outline why this is not the case; in fact, the distribution of the counts of such `good’ partitions into $q$ parts is asymptotically Poisson. This is joint work with Paul Balister, Emil Powierski and Alex Scott.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/28/tan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/28/tan.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>7 February 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Latin square of order $n$ is an $n$ by $n$ grid filled with $n$ symbols, so
that every symbol appears exactly once in each row and each column. A
transversal of a Latin square is a collection of cells in the grid which
share no row, column or symbol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ryser-Brualdi-Stein conjecture says that every Latin square of order
$n$ has a transversal with $n-1$ cells if $n$ is even and with $n$ cells if $n$ is
odd. Recently, Keevash, Pokrovskiy, Sudakov and Yepremyan broke a
long-standing bound on this problem by showing that every Latin square
of order $n$ has a transversal with $n-O(\log n/\log \log n)$ cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will discuss how to make further progress on this problem, and in
particular the challenges of using absorption techniques in this setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/02/07/montgomery.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>31 January 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A well known theorem due to Van der Waerden and dating from 1927 states that in any finite
colouring of the natural numbers there exist arbitrarily long monochromatic arithmetic progressions. Most
Ramsey-theoretical results (finite colourings) have a canonical version. In this setting, the palette of colours
may be infinite but one still would like to characterize all unavoidable sub-structures. For example, the
canonical Van der Waerden’s Theorem, first proved by Erdős and Graham, states that in any colouring
of $[N]$ there exist either arbitrarily long monochromatic arithmetic progressions or arbitrarily long rainbow
arithmetic progressions. In this talk, we shall talk about a canonical version of the polynomial Van der
Waerden’s Theorem, originally proved by Bergelson and Liebman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/girao.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/01/31/girao.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>6 December 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let $M_n$ be drawn uniformly from all $n$ by $n$ symmetric matrices with coefficients in {$-1,1$}. We consider the following basic problem: what is the probability $M_n$ is singular? In this talk I will discuss some recent joint work with Marcelo Campos, Matthew Jenssen and Marcus Michelen, where we show the singularity probability is exponentially small. At the heart of the proof is a combinatorial “decoupling” lemma which I suspect has applications well beyond the scope of our work.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/06/sahasrabudhe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/12/06/sahasrabudhe.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
