<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>4 December 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/04/kronenberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/04/kronenberg.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>20 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/20/bowen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/20/bowen.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>13 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/13/pehova.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/13/pehova.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>30 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/30/portier.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/30/portier.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>23 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/23/janzer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/23/janzer.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>16 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/16/krivelevich.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/16/krivelevich.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>16 May 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The theory of rapid mixing random walks plays a fundamental role in the study of modern randomised algorithms. Usually, the mixing time is measured with respect to the worst initial position. It is well known that the presence of bottlenecks in a graph hampers mixing and, in particular, starting inside a small bottleneck significantly slows down the diffusion of the walk in the first steps of the process. To circumvent this problem, the average mixing time is defined to be the mixing time starting at a uniformly random vertex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk we discuss a general framework to show logarithmic average mixing time for random walks on graphs with small bottlenecks. The framework is especially effective on certain families of random graphs with heterogeneous properties. We demonstrate its applicability on two random models for which the mixing time was known to be of order $\log^2n$, speeding up the mixing to order $\log n$. First, in the context of smoothed analysis on connected graphs, we show logarithmic average mixing time for randomly perturbed graphs of bounded degeneracy. A particular instance is the Newman-Watts small-world model. Second, we show logarithmic average mixing time for supercritically percolated expander graphs. When the host graph is complete, this application gives an alternative proof that the average mixing time of the giant component in the supercritical Erdős-Rényi graph is logarithmic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This represents joint work with Alberto Espuny Díaz, Guillem Perarnau and Oriol Serra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in 25 Gordon Street, Room 500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/05/16/morris.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/05/16/morris.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>9 May 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let $p$ be a prime integer, let $1 \le t &amp;lt; d &amp;lt; p$ be integers, and let $S$ be a non-empty subset of $\mathbb{F}_p$ (which may be thought of as being {$0,1$}). We will establish that if a polynomial $P:\mathbb{F}_p^n \to \mathbb{F}_p$ with degree $d$ is such that the image $P(S^n)$ does not contain the full image $A(\mathbb{F}_p)$ of any non-constant polynomial $A: \mathbb{F}_p \to \mathbb{F}_p$ with degree at most $t$, then $P$ coincides on $S^n$ with a polynomial $Q$ that can be decomposed as a sum of a bounded number of polynomials which each have degree at most $d$ and are products of polynomials that have degrees at most $\lfloor d/(t+1) \rfloor$. In particular the polynomial $Q$ has bounded degree-$\lfloor d/(t+1) \rfloor$-rank in the sense of Green and Tao. Likewise, we will prove that if the assumption holds even for $t=d$ then $P$ coincides on $S^n$ with a polynomial with degree at most $d$ and depending only on a bounded number of variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in 25 Gordon Street, Room 500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/05/09/karam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/05/09/karam.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>21 March 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A subset $A$ of a group is said to be product free if for all elements $a,b$ in $A$ their product $ab$ is not in $A$. In 1985 Babai and Sós posed the problem of determining the largest product free sets in the alternating group. We solve this problem completely when $n$ is sufficiently large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our proof combines representation theory with a recent machinery we developed called `hypercontractvity for global functions’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/03/21/lifshitz.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/03/21/lifshitz.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>14 March 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: In the euclidean space setting, symmetrization inequalities have been quite useful in solving problems coming from various parts of analysis: spectral geometry, variational problems, mathematical physics, spectral theory, to name a few. This theory is very classical and a lot is known in the continuum. In my talk, I will discuss about discrete analogues of these inequalities on graphs. This is a fairly new topic, and there is hardly anything known in this setting. I will talk about recent developments that has happened in the last one year, connections of this theory with different types of isoperimetric inequalities on graphs. Apart from general theory, I will present some concrete results for standard graph on $2d$ integer lattices. The talk will be at the interface of discrete math and analysis, and will be  based on a joint work with Stefan Steinerberger: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arXiv.org/abs/2212.07590&quot;&gt; arXiv:2212.07590&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/03/14/gupta.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/03/14/gupta.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
