<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>11 December 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Foster Court room 114.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/11/dhawan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/11/dhawan.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>4 December 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 822.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/04/kronenberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/04/kronenberg.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>27 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A graph is called $d$-rigid if there exists an embedding of its vertex set into $\mathbb{R}^d$ such that every continuous motion of the vertices that preserves the lengths of all edges actually preserves the distances between all pairs of vertices. In this talk, I will present new sufficient conditions for the $d$-rigidity of a graph in terms of the existence of “rigid partitions” - partitions of the graph that satisfy certain connectivity properties. Following this, I will outline several broadly applicable conditions for the existence of rigid partitions and discuss a few applications, among which are new results on the rigidity of highly-connected, (pseudo)random graphs, and dense graphs. In particular, I will show that $Cd^2\log^2(n)$-connected $n$-vertex graphs are $d$-rigid, a result that can be viewed as a step towards the Lovász-Yemini conjecture, which states that $Cd^2$-connected graphs are $d$-rigid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk is based on joint work with Michael Krivelevich and Alan Lew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 780.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/27/michaeli.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/27/michaeli.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>20 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We discuss a technique for obtaining new Ramsey theorems from the compositions of old ones. As our simplest application, we show that any finite coloring of $\mathbb{N}$ contains arbitrarily large $A,B\subset \mathbb{N}$ with $(A+B)\cup (A\cdot B)$ monochromatic, addressing a problem of Kra, Moreira, Richter, and Robertson. More generally, we also prove iterated versions of this, finding monochromatic sets such as ${A \circ_1 (B \circ_2 C): \circ_i\in {+,\cdot}} $ and a variety of mixed arithmetic and geometric versions of van der Waerden’s theorem, finding monochromatic sets such as ${a+id, c\cdot ad^i: i\leq k}$ and ${a(b+ic)^j: i,j\leq k}.$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 822.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/20/bowen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/20/bowen.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>15 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We prove that given a finite collection of cylinders in $\mathbb{R}^3$ with the property that any two of them intersect, there is a line intersecting an $\alpha$-fraction of the cylinders where $\alpha=1/14$. This is a special case of an interesting conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 639 at 3-4pm.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/15/barany.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/15/barany.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>13 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent paper from 2020 Joos and Kim showed that every collection of n graphs $G_1,…,G_n$ on a common vertex set $[n]$ with minimum degree at least $n/2$ contains a Hamilton cycle using exactly one edge from each graph. Such a Hamilton cycle is called transversal, or rainbow. This result directly extends Dirac’s theorem, which can be deduced by taking all graphs in the collection to be isomorphic, and kick-started a systematic study of transversal problems in extremal combinatorics. We show that (asymptotically) the same degree condition guarantees not only a single rainbow Hamilton cycle, but in fact every rainbow Hamilton cycle. That is, if all $G_i$ have minimum degree $(1/2+\varepsilon)n$ for some small $\varepsilon$, then there is a Hamilton cycle $C=e_1…e_n$ whose edges $e_i$ are taken in the natural cyclic ordering, such that each $e_i$ is in $E(G_i)$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Candida Bowtell, Patrick Morris and Katherine Staden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 639.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/13/pehova.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/13/pehova.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>6 November 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Garbe, Hladký, Šileikis and Skerman recently introduced a
class of discrete-time random graph processes called flip processes. A
flip process starts with a given $n$-vertex graph, and each step of a flip
process involves randomly selecting a $k$-tuple of distinct vertices and
modifying the induced subgraph according to a predetermined rule. It was
proved by Garbe, Hladký, Šileikis and Skerman that the typical behaviour
of flip processes correspond to certain continuous-time deterministic
graphon trajectories. In this talk I will discuss recent work towards
characterising flip process rules with the same trajectories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 639.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/06/hng.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/06/hng.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>30 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Rademacher sum is a finite weighted sum of independent Rademacher random variables, that is $R=a_1\epsilon_1+\dots+a_n\epsilon_n$ 
where the $a_i$ are real constants and $\epsilon_i$ are picked independently and uniformly at random from ${-1,+1}$. 
Tomaszewski’s conjecture from 1986 states that every Rademacher sum $R$ of variance 1 satisfies $\mathbb{P}(|R| \leq 1) \geq 1/2$. This problem has attracted significant attention over the years before it was finally settled by Keller and Klein in 2020. 
Tomaszewski’s counterpart problem is concerned with determining $\inf \mathbb{P}(|R| \geq 1)$, where the infimum is taken over the class of Rademacher sums $R$ of variance 1. This problem has also received much attention over the years, with Hitczenko and Kwapień conjecturing in 1994 that the infimum is $7/32$. In this talk we confirm Hitczenko and Kwapień’s conjecture. In fact, our methods enable us to fully determine $f(y)= \inf \mathbb{P}(|R| \geq y\sqrt{\mathrm{Var}(R)})$ where the infimum is taken over all Rademacher sums $R$, confirming a conjecture by Lowther and giving a partial answer to a question by Keller and Klein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Lawrence Hollom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 104 (Elvin Hall).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/30/portier.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/30/portier.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>23 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The tree packing conjecture of Gyárfás from 1976 says that any sequence of trees $T_1,\ldots,T_n$ such that $|T_i|=i$ for each $i$ packs into $K_n$.
Packing even just the largest trees in such a sequence has proven difficult, with Bollobás drawing attention to this in 1995 by conjecturing that, for each $k$, if $n$ is sufficiently large then the largest $k$ trees in any such sequence can be packed. Despite many partial results and much related work on the full tree packing conjecture, even this weakening remained open. We prove Bollobás’s conjecture, by showing that, moreover, a linear number of the largest trees can be packed in the tree packing conjecture. Joint work with Richard Montgomery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Bedford Way (20) room 639.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/23/janzer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/23/janzer.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>16 October 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Clément replaces &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.tau.ac.il/~krivelev&quot;&gt;Michael Krivelevich&lt;/a&gt; whose talk was cancelled due to the situation in Israel following Hamas’s horrific attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An infinite graph is quasi-transitive if its vertex set has finitely many orbits under the action of its automorphism group. We obtain a structure theorem for locally finite quasi-transitive graphs avoiding a minor, which is reminiscent of the Robertson-Seymour Graph Minor Structure Theorem. As applications of this result, we prove that every locally finite quasi-transitive graph attains its Hadwiger number, that is, if such a graph contains arbitrarily large clique minors, then it contains an infinite clique minor. This answers a question of Thomassen from 1992. We also derive some results on the accessibility of quasi-transitive graphs and groups avoiding a minor. Finally, we prove the minor-excluded case of a conjecture of Ballier and Stein (2018) on the domino problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Foster Court room 114.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/16/legrand-duchesne.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/16/legrand-duchesne.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
