<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>5 December 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Gordon Square (26) Room B32.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/06/patel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/12/06/patel.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>29 November 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a small graph $F$, what is the maximum number of induced copies of $F$ that an $n$-vertex graph can contain, and what does a graph with many copies look like? This is the inducibility problem introduced by Pippenger and Golumbic in 1975, which is still wide open for most $F$. I will give a survey of the area and will mention some of the latest results, including joint work with Hong Liu, Oleg Pikhurko and Maryam Sharifzadeh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/29/staden.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/29/staden.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>22 November 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let us call a graph/hypergraph $G$ extremal if there exists a finite family $F$ such that $G$ is an $F$-free graph with the maximum number of edges. The classical Erdős–Stone-Simonovitsz theorem implies that Turan graphs approximate all extremal graphs in edit distance. This talk is an invitation to its analogue in the hypergraph setting: what hypergraphs can approximate all extremal hypergraphs? I’ll mention some related results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/22/liu.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/22/liu.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>15 November 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/15/johnston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/15/johnston.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2 November 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk I will discuss some recent work examining the extremal relationship between two well-studied graph parameters: the order of the largest homogeneous set in a graph $G$ and the maximal number of distinct degrees appearing in an induced subgraph of $G$, denoted respectively by $\mathrm{hom}(G)$ and $f(G)$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main theorem improves estimates due to Bukh and Sudakov and to Narayanan and Tomon and shows that if $G$ is an $n$-vertex graph with $\mathrm{hom} (G)$ at least $n^{1/2}$ then $f(G) &amp;gt; ( n / \mathrm{hom} (G) )^{1 - o(1)}$. The bound here is sharp up to the $o(1)$-term, and asymptotically solves a conjecture of Narayanan and Tomon. In particular, this implies that $\max ( \mathrm{hom} (G), f(G) ) &amp;gt; n^{1/2 -o(1)}$ for any $n$-vertex graph $G$, which is also sharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between these parameters is known to change when $\mathrm{hom}(G) &amp;lt; n^{1/2}$. I hope to discuss the suspected relationship in this other region, along with supporting results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joint work with Laurențiu Ploscaru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be in Foster Court Room 243.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/02/long.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/02/long.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>25 October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;regular bipartite tournament&lt;/em&gt; is an orientation of a complete
balanced bipartite graph $K_{2n,2n}$ where every vertex has its in- and
outdegree both equal to $n$. In 1981, Jackson conjectured that any
regular bipartite tournament can be decomposed into Hamilton cycles. We
prove this conjecture for sufficiently large $n$. Along the way, we also
prove several further results, including a conjecture of Liebenau and
Pehova on Hamilton decompositions of dense bipartite digraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/25/granet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/25/granet.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>18 October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A factorisation $x = u_1u_2\ldots$ of an infinite word $x$ on alphabet $X$ is called ‘super-monochromatic’, for a given colouring of the finite
words $X^∗$ on alphabet $X$, if each word $u_{k_1} u_{k_2} \ldots u_{k_n}$, where $k_1 &amp;lt; · · · &amp;lt; k_n$,
is the same colour. A direct application of Hindman’s theorem shows that
if $x$ is eventually periodic, then for every finite colouring of $X^∗$, there exist a suffix of $x$ that admits a super-monochromatic factorisation. What
about the converse?
In this talk we show that the converse does indeed hold: thus a word $x$ is eventually periodic if and only if for every finite colouring of $X^∗$
there is a suffix of $x$ having a super-monochromatic factorisation. This
has been a conjecture in the community for some time. Our main tool
is a Ramsey result about alternating sums. This provides a strong link
between Ramsey theory and the combinatorics of infinite words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joint work with Imre Leader and Luca Q. Zamboni&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/18/ivan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/18/ivan.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>11 October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The focal point of this talk is the recently found connection between two completely different corners of mathematics: multiple orthogonal polynomials, an extension of standard orthogonal polynomials developed and studied by the special-functions community, and branched continued fractions, a generalisation of continued fractions arising from the combinatorics of lattice paths and introduced by the enumerative-combinatorics community to solve total-positivity problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we revisit the classical connection between lattice paths, continued fractions, and orthogonal polynomials. Then, we discuss our ongoing research on an extension of this connection linking lattice paths, branched continued fractions, and multiple orthogonal polynomials. This work is part of a collaboration with Alan Sokal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/11/lima.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/11/lima.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>4 October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I will consider selection rules that map any directed graph (without loops) to a subset of its vertices. A selection rule is impartial if the selection of a vertex is independent of its outgoing edges, and an optimal impartial rule is one that in any graph selects vertices with large degrees. The idea is that vertices and edges represent individuals and nominations among invidiuals, and we want to select highly nominated individuals without individuals having an influence on their own selection. I will discuss what is know about impartial selection and point to some open problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk is based on joint work with Noga Alon, Antje Bjelde, Javier Cembrano, David Hannon, Max Klimm, Ariel Procaccia, and Moshe Tennenholtz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will in &lt;b&gt;Gordon Square (24) Room 105 at 2:30–3:30&lt;/b&gt;.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/04/fischer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/10/04/fischer.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>27 September 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a collection of hypergraphs $\mathcal{H}=(H_1, \ldots, H_m)$ with the same vertex set, an $m$-edge graph $F\subset \cup_{i\in [m]}H_i$ is a transversal if there is a bijection $\phi:E(F)\to [m]$ such that $e\in E(H_{\phi(e)})$ for each $e\in E(F)$. How large does the minimum degree of each $H_i$ need to be so that $\mathcal{H}$ necessarily contains a copy of $F$ that is a transversal? Each $H_i$ in the collection could be the same hypergraph, hence the minimum degree of each $H_i$ needs to be large enough to ensure that $F\subseteq H_i$. Since its general introduction by Joos and Kim, a growing body of work has shown that in many cases, this lower bound is tight. In this paper, we give a unified approach to this problem by giving a widely applicable sufficient condition for this lower bound to be asymptotically tight. This is general enough to recover many previous results in the area and obtain novel transversal variants of several classical Dirac-type results for (powers of) Hamiltn cycles. For example, we derive that any collection of $2n$ graphs on an $n$-vertex set, each with minimum degree at least $(2/3+o(1))n$, contains a transversal copy of the square of a Hamilton cycle. This can be viewed as a rainbow version of Pósa’s conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is joint work with Pranshu Gupta, Fabian Hamann, Olaf Parczyk, and Amedeo Sgueglia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will be held online, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucl.zoom.us/j/94328070777&quot;&gt;https://ucl.zoom.us/j/94328070777&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/09/27/muyesser.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/09/27/muyesser.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
